CAPA:
Our sun is dying.
Mankind faces extinction.
Seven years ago, the Icarus Project
sent a mission to restart the sun.
But that mission was lost
before it reached the star.
Sixteen months ago, I, Robert Capa,
and a crew of seven...
...left Earth frozen in a solar winter.
Our payload...
...a stellar bomb with a mass
equivalent to Manhattan Island.
Our purpose...
...to create a star within a star.
[RUMBLING]
Eight astronauts strapped
to the back of a bomb.
My bomb.
Welcome to Icarus II.
SEARLE:
Icarus.
ICARUS [OVER COMMUNICATOR]:
Yes, Dr. Searle?
Please re-filter
the Observation Room portal.
ICARUS:
Filter up or down, Dr. Searle?
Down.
Oh, my.
Icarus, how close is this
to full brightness?
ICARUS:
At this distance of 36 million miles...
...you are observing the sun
at 2 percent of full brightness.
Two percent?
Can you show me 4 percent?
ICARUS: Four percent would result in
irreversible damage to your retinas.
[RUMBLING]
ICARUS: However, you could observe
3.1 percent...
...for a period of not longer than
30 seconds.
All right. Icarus, I'm gonna reset...
...the filter to 3.1 percent.
[GASPS]
[CHUCKLES]
SEARLE:
Well, it's invigorating.
It's like taking a shower in light.
-You lose yourself a little.
-Like a flotation tank.
Actually, no.
MACE:
Look, what is it, beef?
Chicken.
If you don't like it,
you take my shift next time.
For psych tests on deep space,
I ran sensory-deprivation trials.
Testing total darkness
on flotation tanks.
And the point about darkness is,
you float in it.
You and the darkness are distinct
from each other...
...because darkness is an absence
of something, it's a vacuum.
But total light, it envelops you.
It becomes you.
It's very strange. I don't, um--
I recommend it.
What's strange, Searle,
is that you're the psych officer...
...and I'm clearly a lot saner
than you are.
CORAZON:
Mmm. Good.
All right, if no one's gonna say it,
I'm going to.
The solar wind reading is much higher
than we'd anticipated at this distance.
For the moment we can still send
package messages back.
High-frequency bursts will rise
above interference...
...and the Moon Stations
will be able to pick them up.
But it's possible that within 24 hours
we won't be able to communicate at all.
Possible?
Probable.
We'll finally be on our own.
We're 55 million miles from Earth.
I'd say we're already on our own.
KANEDA:
Come on, guys. We were expecting this.
No great drama.
We're flying into the dead zone...
...seven days sooner
than we thought.
But if any of you are planning
on sending a final message home...
...you should do it now.
[SIGHS]
Uh, well, Mom and Dad.
Uh, I hope you're proud of your son...
...saving mankind and so on.
[WATER TRICKLING]
By the time you get this message,
I'll be in the dead zone.
It came a little sooner
than we thought.
But this means that you won't be able
to send a message back.
So I just wanted to let you know
that I don't need the message.
Because I know everything
you wanna say.
Just remember it takes eight minutes
for light to travel from sun to Earth.
Which means you'll know
we've succeeded...
...about eight minutes
after we deliver the payload.
All you have to do is look out
for a little extra brightness in the sky.
So, if you wake up one morning,
and it's a particularly beautiful day...
...you'll know we made it.
Okay.
I'm signing out.
And I'll see you in a couple of years.
CORAZON: Ugh.
Icarus, dial it down a little, will you?
ICARUS:
Yes, Corazon.
CORAZON:
Captain?
I'm guessing you've been
talking to Searle.
-So, do you have that report for me?
-Yeah.
Right here.
The O2 productivity is good. In fact,
if anything, we're over-producing.
It will trail off dramatically
when we get nearer.
But in truth, we have the reserves
to make it there and a quarter-way back.
You're thinking about Icarus I.
Well, whatever it was
that tripped them up...
...I don't think
it was a lack of oxygen.
Not on the outward journey,
at any rate.
[MACE AND CAPA GRUNTING]
MACE:
Fuck.
TREY: Mace.
HARVEY: Mace.
TREY: What are you doing?
HARVEY: Come on.
-Fuck.
HARVEY: Relax. Put it down.
MACE:
You son of a bitch.
MACE: Fucker took an hour in there.
HARVEY: Stop.
I can't send my package,
the wind is too high.
HARVEY: Calm down.
CAPA: I'm sorry, all right? Jesus.
Kaneda, Searle, report to Flight Deck.
KANEDA:
What's up?
We have an excess of manliness
breaking out in the Comms Center.
So how does this work?
MACE [ON MONITOR]: Am I supposed to
tell you about my childhood?
SEARLE: I probably know more
about your childhood than you do.
MACE:
It's the time.
Sixteen months,
you can get used to anything.
You just...
...lose track.
I know I fucked up.
From now on...
...I'm not gonna lose track again.
SEARLE:
Prescription...
...Earth Room.
Two hours?
-And get a haircut, Mace.
-Yeah.
[ALL LAUGHING AND SCREAMING]
[BEEPS]
MACE:
Bring back the waves.
ICARUS: Dr. Searle's prescription
specifies a peaceful module.
The waves make me feel peaceful.
[ALL LAUGHING AND SCREAMING]
Again.
[DOOR BEEPS]
[CAPA SIGHS]
Mace, I'm sorry.
I should have let you go first.
Capa. It's me.
I'm the one apologizing, all right?
All right.
-Was that the apology?
-Yeah.
-Consider it accepted.
-Okay.
[CORAZON CHUCKLES]
It was a sequence of contact reports
on the top-left shield quadrant...
...which, by 1700, had turned
into a minor asteroid storm.
None bigger than a raindrop...
...but we had 19 punctures...
...and a secondary contact
to the engine compartment.
Took three alpha shifts to patch it up.
Lost a little vapor. Nothing serious.
I watched them hit us
from the Observation Room.
Gotta tell you, Moon Base, it was, uh--
It was...
...beautiful.
Gotta tell you, Moon Base, it was, uh--
It was...
...beautiful.
ICARUS: Mace?
MACE: Yeah.
Your maintenance program
allows a further 14 minutes...
...for the mainframe panel
to remain out of coolant tank.
MACE:
Shit.
[GROANS]
CASSIE:
Guys...
...you wanna see something?
[CREW CHEERING AND CLAPPING]
KANEDA: Well, I should have
a few words to say...
...but on reflection...
...what can one say?
Ladies and gentlemen.
Mercury.
[FAINT BEEPING]
[BEEPING LOUDER]
Twenty-three hours ago,
on the comms systems--
While listening to your space music?
--while scanning the frequencies,
I heard a transmission.
It appeared as we flew
into the dark side of Mercury.
The iron content of the planet...
...is acting as an antenna.
There's high background interference,
but the signal is clear enough.
Icarus, please play audio file 7-5/B.
ICARUS:
Yes, Harvey.
[SIGNAL BEEPING]
[SIGNAL REPEATS]
HARVEY:
End file.
What is it?
It's the Icarus I.
That signal is their distress beacon.
Jesus.
That's impossible.
It's been seven years.
Clearly it's not impossible
because you can hear it.
-They're still alive?
-We don't know.
CORAZON: But they could be.
Oxygen is self-replenishing.
Water is recycled.
They have the solar power
they need.
What about food?
Their supplies couldn't last.
KANEDA:
That depends.
They had stock to cover eight people
for three years.
That's a four-year shortfall.
Hell of a diet.
KANEDA: We don't know
what happened to Icarus I.
There might have been an accident.
There might not have been
eight people to feed.
-Captain, do we know where they are?
-Well done, Capa. That is the question.
Icarus.
Please plot our trajectory following
the slingshot around Mercury.
ICARUS:
Yes, captain.
KANEDA: Now plot the source
of the Icarus I beacon.
[SIGNAL BEEPING]
Jesus. They almost made it.
KANEDA: That's why no one picked up
the signal until now.
It was lost in the background light
and noise.
We're gonna pass right by them.
KANEDA:
Within 10 or 15 thousand miles.
CASSIE:
Can anyone survive?
KANEDA:
If the shield is intact.
We'll be able to see them?
Yes.
I'd need to look at all of this
pretty carefully. Very carefully.
But if I had to make a guess right now,
I'd say we could adjust our trajectory.
We could fly straight to them.
But we're not gonna do that.
Just to make it absolutely clear,
there's no way we're gonna do that.
Do I have to spell it out for you?
We have a payload to deliver
to the heart of our nearest star.
We're doing it
because that star is dying.
And if it dies, we die.
Everything dies.
So that is our mission.
There is nothing...
...literally nothing, more important than
completing our mission. End of story.
-He's right.
-He's right. Of course I'm right.
Is anyone here seriously
considering otherwise?
-May I put a counter argument?
-No.
Captain?
Go ahead.
SEARLE:
It would, of course...
...be absurd to alter our trajectory
to assist the crew of the Icarus I.
Even if we knew that some or
even all of that crew are still alive...
...their lives are expendable
when seen in the context of our mission.
As are our own lives.
-Exactly.
SEARLE: However...
...there is something onboard the
Icarus I that may be worth the detour.
As you pointed out, Mace,
we have a payload to deliver.
A payload. Singular.
Now, everything about the delivery
and effectiveness of that payload...
...is entirely theoretical.
Simply put...
...we don't know if it's gonna work.
But what we do know is this...
...if we had two bombs,
we'd have two chances.
HARVEY: You're assuming
we'd be able to pilot Icarus I.
-Yes.
TREY: Which is assuming...
...that whatever stopped them wasn't
a fault or a damage to the spacecraft.
-Yes.
-It's a lot of assumptions.
SEARLE:
It is.
It's a risk assessment.
The question is:
Does the risk of a detour outweigh
the benefits of an extra payload?
-We'll have a vote.
SEARLE: No, no.
No, we won't.
We are not a democracy.
We're a collection of astronauts
and scientists.
So we're gonna make the most
informed decision available to us.
Made by you, by any chance?
Made by the person best qualified
to understand the complexities...
...of a payload delivery.
Our physicist.
Shit.
CAPA: Okay, Icarus, run the math on
the successful delivery of the payload.
ICARUS:
Okay, payload delivery point reached.
CAPA:
Detach the payload.
ICARUS:
Stellar bomb initiated and detached.
Crew and living section
have four minutes...
...to clear and commence
homeward journey.
CAPA: And four minutes after
separation, boosters automatically fire.
ICARUS: Payload boosters will
automatically fire after four-minute delay.
Entering coronal hole
in South Polar Cap.
Magnetic field structure open.
Temperature, 37,000.
Reliability of projection has dropped
below 45 percent.
Remaining projection is not open
to useful speculation.
Variables infinite.
Accuracy unknown.
That's the problem right there.
Between the boosters
and the gravity of the sun...
...the velocity will be so great...
...space and time
will become smeared together.
Everything will distort,
everything will be unquantifiable.
KANEDA: You have to come down
on one side or the other.
-I need a decision.
-It's not a decision, it's a guess.
It's like flipping a coin and asking me
to decide whether it'll be heads or tails.
KANEDA:
And?
Heads.
We've mined all Earth's fissile
materials for this bomb.
There's not gonna be
another payload.
The one we carry is our last chance.
Our last best hope.
Searle's argument is sound.
Two last hopes are better than one.
That's it.
ICARUS:
Slingshot complete.
Icarus leaving Mercury orbit.
[CAPA SCREAMING]
[CAPA GASPS]
Hey.
CASSIE:
Good dream?
Let me guess.
The surface of the sun?
Only dream I ever have.
Every time I shut my eyes
it's always the same.
Maybe you should talk
to Dr. Searle about that.
See if he can help you out.
[LAUGHS]
Maybe.
I just wanted to let you know...
...I think you made the right decision.
Well.
Mace doesn't and I'm guessing Harvey
and Trey don't either.
CASSIE:
Yeah...
...but I do.
[ALARM BEEPING]
KANEDA: Get the alarm. What's going on?
-I screwed up.
MACE:
It's not you. It's my responsibility.
-We shouldn't be straying.
KANEDA: Trey, cut to it.
In order to change the route,
I had to manually override Icarus.
So I made all the calculations myself.
And I double- and triple-checked them.
They all worked out.
So I set the new coordinates
and put us on our way.
What's the problem?
The trajectory is wrong?
The trajectory is good.
But it changes our angle of approach
to the sun by 1.1 degrees.
You didn't reset the shields
to the new angle.
Jesus Christ, Trey.
I forgot.
My head was full of velocities and fuel
calculations and a million different--
I forgot, all right?
People do shit.
They get stressed...
...and fuck up.
I fucked up.
Trey.
The fact is, we're still alive.
A hole hasn't burnt
in the side of the ship.
We don't have
a 10,000-degree climate.
-So, what's the actual damage?
-We don't know.
Icarus tried to reset the shields
independently when the alarm triggered.
But all the sensors up there are
burned out.
So we have no idea of the state
of the affected area.
Only way we're gonna know
is if we go out there.
Okay.
I'll get suited up.
It's a two-man job.
As second in command,
you're not going anywhere.
-I volunteer.
MACE: No, I volunteer.
Fine.
I volunteer Capa.
Sure.
I'll do it.
Okay.
[CAPA SIGHS]
You've done this a thousand times
in Earth-orbit training.
Yeah.
You're gonna be fine.
Okay?
CASSIE:
Okay, Icarus.
I'm gonna be taking
control for a while.
ICARUS: Okay, Cassie.
CASSIE: I'm gonna be cutting speed.
I'm gonna rotate us so the damage
is facing away from the sun.
-Do we understand each other?
ICARUS: Yes, Cassie.
Rotate by that much, we're gonna
lose Comm Towers 3 and 4.
MACE: Well, it's a good thing
we don't need them, then.
We don't need them now,
we're gonna need them to go home.
We'll cross that bridge when
we come to it.
In the meantime, I'm gonna try and
give them as much shadow as I can.
MACE:
All right, guys.
I'm opening up.
Okay.
KANEDA [OVER COMM]:
Helmet-cam operational.
MACE [OVER COMM]:
Affirmative. Good image.
Capa, check,
helmet-cam fully operational.
MACE:
Affirmative.
[CAPA PANTING]
CAPA: Exiting airlock
with maintenance modules.
Moving down
to investigate damaged area.
Okay, guys.
Nice and easy.
KANEDA:
Copy.
CASSIE: Icarus, please adjust shield
to allow for rotation.
ICARUS:
Yes, Cassie.
[RUMBLING]
ICARUS:
Establishing new alignment to sun.
CORAZON:
Jesus.
MACE: That's the temperature change
on the shields.
The metal's just contracting
and expanding.
I know what it is, flyboy.
[RUMBLING]
It sounds like she's tearing apart.
ICARUS: Fatal damage
to Comms Towers 3 and 4.
MACE: Copy, Icarus. Loss of towers
3 and 4. Cancel alarm.
Shut down sensor
to Comms Tower 3 and 4.
KANEDA [OVER COMM]:
You should see it up here, guys.
It's pretty impressive.
Okay.
There are four damaged panels.
They're about 300 meters out.
Capa, take it easy. You're going
through your O2 pretty fast.
Oh. Copy that, Cory.
That's it.
Slow down the breathing.
Relaxed movement.
KANEDA:
Approaching the first panel.
We were lucky.
Can you guys see this?
We can see it.
The hydraulics are burnt out.
Let's get this closed.
Okay, Mace.
That's it.
That's the first one closed.
You can do it?
KANEDA:
It'll take a while, but--
Yeah.
We can do it.
[ALL CHEERING]
HARVEY:
Great job.
MACE: Lots of smiling faces
in this room, guys.
HARVEY: Great job.
CASSIE: I love you, captain.
KANEDA:
Moving to next panel.
Three to go.
MACE:
Hey.
[BOTH CHUCKLING]
Don't kill yourself, man.
We got this, okay?
CAPA: Whoa!
-What's going on, guys?
The ship's moving.
We're venting O2. Shit.
I think we're venting O2.
ICARUS: Resuming computer control
of Icarus II.
Negative, Icarus. Manual control.
ICARUS:
Negative, Cassie. Computer control.
-Returning vessel to original rotation.
-What?
Icarus, override computer
to manual control.
ICARUS:
Negative. Mission in jeopardy.
Override command statement to
manual flight controls removed.
MACE: Why?
CASSIE: Negative, Icarus.
Negative. State reason immediately.
ICARUS:
Fire in oxygen garden.
No.
HARVEY:
Seal oxygen feed.
-Fireguard perimeter.
CASSIE: Sealing sector. Sealing feed.
-Seal sections five through nine.
-Sealing five through nine.
Kaneda, Capa,
get back to the airlock now.
Can't.
Can't leave upright panels.
The ship will burn up if the shields
are not repaired.
TREY: They're gonna die.
HARVEY: Don't.
-They're gonna burn.
-They are not.
Override Icarus. Cassie, pilot...
...emergency command 0-0-0.
ICARUS:
Copy command 0-0-0.
-Second human confirmation required.
CASSIE: Copy.
Mace?
Wait, Cassie.
Jesus Christ, Harvey.
Harvey, comms officer,
confirm back-up 0-0-0.
ICARUS:
Override command confirmed.
Manual control returned.
No.
Icarus, continue procedure.
CASSIE:
What?
MACE:
Captain.
-Back me up.
KANEDA: Copy, Mace.
Crew priority
is to protect the payload.
Get the fire out.
Icarus, take control of the ship.
ICARUS: Affirmative, captain.
HARVEY: Damn it.
ICARUS:
Returning vessel to original rotation.
CORAZON: Let me in. Please.
ICARUS: Negative.
Door sealed by operating superior
comms officer.
CORAZON [OVER PA]:
You motherfucker.
Let me in.
ICARUS:
Hazard diagnostic complete.
Sprinkler system failing.
Fire will burn for six hours.
Sixty percent chance
of containment failure.
Seventy-five percent chance of collateral
damage to life-support systems.
HARVEY:
What are we gonna do?
MACE: Flood it with O2.
-What?
It'll cause a flashover.
Make it burn itself out.
We'll lose the whole garden.
We already lost it.
HARVEY:
Jesus, Mace, I don't know.
Icarus, open the O2 tanks.
MACE [OVER PA]:
Cory, get the hell out of there.
ICARUS:
Opening O2 tanks.
CORAZON:
No.
[CORAZON SOBBING]
ICARUS: Eighty-nine percent of shield
in full sunlight.
KANEDA:
Capa, go back.
I'll finish this.
Please, I can do this.
Go.
Capa returning to airlock.
Do you copy?
CASSIE:
Copy, Capa. Hurry.
ICARUS: Ninety-one percent of shield
in full sunlight.
Ninety-four percent of shield
Captain? Captain?
I'm at the edge of the shield.
Do you copy?
Captain, you must leave now.
Captain?
ICARUS: Ninety-seven percent of shield
in full sunlight.
KANEDA: Final panel closing.
The shield is secure.
You have to move now.
Captain, it's right on you.
-Kaneda's not gonna make it.
CAPA: You have to move.
You have to move now.
It's too far.
CAPA:
Captain, move.
Why isn't he moving?
SEARLE:
Kaneda.
What do you see?
Searle, tell our captain to move.
Kaneda, what can you see?
Searle, do you copy?
Kaneda?
[SCREAMING]
[PANTING]
ICARUS:
Shield rotation complete.
HARVEY:
The breakdown is as follows.
Trey is sedated in the Med Centre.
Dr. Searle has diagnosed him
as a suicide risk.
I don't think any of us
are about to question that diagnosis.
As second in command,
I am now the captain of Icarus II.
Thanks both to Kaneda...
...and Capa, our shields are intact.
As is the payload.
But the oxygen garden
is totally destroyed.
In addition, a large amount of O2
was burned in the fire.
As it stands now...
...we don't have enough oxygen reserves
to get us to our payload delivery point.
Let alone to survive
the return journey.
So cancel the ticker-tape parade.
We now have no choice
but to rendezvous with Icarus I.
If we're gonna complete
the mission...
...the Icarus I is our only hope.
CORAZON:
Technically, he made a mistake.
MACE:
What are you trying to say, Cory?
Harvey said there's not enough oxygen
to get us to the delivery point.
But there is.
There just isn't enough oxygen
to get all of us there.
Are you suggesting
we let Trey kill himself?
No.
And in any case...
...Trey wouldn't be enough.
We need to lose two more.
Three out of seven.
That's a lot of short straws.
CASSIE:
Capa, it's me.
It's different.
Being afraid
that you won't make it back home.
And then knowing that you won't.
CAPA: Our survival depends
on what we can salvage from Icarus I.
No.
We're gonna die out here.
Like the other crew.
I know it.
So do you.
Are you scared?
When the stellar bomb is triggered...
...very little will happen at first.
And then a spark
will pop into existence...
...and it will hang for an instant,
hovering in space. And then...
...it will split into two.
And those will split again...
...and again and again.
Detonation beyond all imagining.
A big bang on a small scale.
A new star born out of a dying one.
I think it'll be beautiful.
No. I'm not scared.
I am.
[DISTRESS SIGNAL BEEPING]
CORAZON [OVER PA]:
Searle, Capa, they're waiting for you.
SEARLE:
Okay, let's go.
MACE:
Be careful, watch your step.
HARVEY:
Cassie, are you getting this on the feed?
CASSIE [OVER COMM]:
Getting what?
HARVEY:
The air. It's full of dust.
SEARLE:
Human skin.
HARVEY:
What?
SEARLE:
Eighty percent of all dust is human skin.
[BANGING]
[ALL GASP]
MACE:
Sorry.
HARVEY: No lights?
MACE: No.
SEARLE:
No surprise.
MACE:
Anyone afraid of the dark?
We should split up.
HARVEY:
I'm not sure that's such a good idea.
MACE:
Yeah, probably right.
Might get picked off one at a time
by aliens.
SEARLE: Icarus I is a big ship. We can't
search it effectively in one group.
HARVEY:
Okay. You're right.
Mace, head up for the Flight Deck,
see if you can't get her to fly.
Searle, check the social area
and the sleeping quarters.
Capa, aim for the payload.
I'll check the garden.
Let's keep in contact, guys.
[LIGHTS POWERING UP]
HARVEY:
Listen up, everybody.
You gotta see this.
Seven years of unchecked growth.
HARVEY [OVER COMM]:
Can you see this?
It's an ecosystem working beautifully
after all this time.
You seeing this readout,
O2, everybody. Ha-ha.
It's wonderful.
HARVEY:
Oh, my God.
Cory, look at the ferns.
MACE:
That's strange.
Subsystems are fine.
Solar harvest is fine.
The ship should be running except I'm
getting nothing from the flight computer.
SEARLE:
Got water.
Food.
No crew.
No bodies.
[HARVEY GRUNTS]
HARVEY:
My God.
You can hardly walk, it's so thick.
PINBACKER [ON MONITOR]:
I am Pinbacker.
Commander of the Icarus I.
We have abandoned our mission.
Our star is dying.
All our science...
...all our hopes...
...our dreams, are foolish.
In the face of this...
...we are...
...dust. Nothing more.
And to this dust, we will return.
When he chooses for us to die...
...it is not our place...
...to challenge God.
MACE:
Okay, that make sense to anyone?
Transmission code is six
and a half years ago.
CORAZON: That would be after
they entered the non-com zone.
That should be the time they
were supposed to deliver the payload.
CAPA:
Payload is fully operational.
Say again, Capa?
The payload is fully operational.
It's A-okay.
That's great news.
Looks like we got what we came for.
MACE:
No, we don't.
CASSIE:
Go ahead, Mace?
MACE:
I know what caused the distress signal.
There's a coolant failure of some kind.
The bottom line is...
...it doesn't matter that Capa
has his payload.
Without the mainframe, we can't fly.
It's been sabotaged.
We should never have
gone off the mission.
SEARLE:
I have something to say.
Found the crew.
CAPA:
What happened?
SEARLE:
They had an epiphany.
They saw the light.
CAPA:
They burned themselves.
MACE:
No shit.
SEARLE: I suspect the observation filter
is fully open.
If we weren't behind the screen
of Icarus II, we'd join them.
Ashes to ashes.
Stardust to stardust.
CASSIE:
Icarus! Whoa!
[RUMBLING]
[ALARMS BLARING]
Icarus. Stabilizers.
[SEARLE GRUNTS]
-What was that?
-Guys, get back to the airlock now.
CASSIE:
We have a major incident.
We are floating free from you.
Repeat, we are floating free.
All crew back to the airlock.
[HARVEY GRUNTING]
-Cassie.
CASSIE: The airlock has decoupled.
We don't know why.
The locking system on Icarus I
is totally ripped open.
I can hold our position but we aren't
gonna be able to dock again.
There's another thing, guys.
You've got a breach, I can see it.
You're losing atmosphere.
CAPA:
We're screwed.
No, we're not.
One of us isn't, anyway.
What happened?
Airlock's destroyed.
There's only one suit. Capa's taking it.
-Why Capa?
-The rest of us are lower priority.
I'm not a low priority.
MACE: You're a comms officer on a ship
that has no communication.
I am the captain.
The mission needs a captain
to hold it together.
Harvey, Capa's the only person outside
of Icarus who can operate the payload.
There is no choice.
No, there's no choice for you.
Capa, I order you to remove that suit.
Get out of the suit.
That is a direct order.
I assure you, when I'm onboard Icarus II
that I'll do everything within my power--
To what?
Shuttle back with more suits?
The airlock is ripped in half.
Once we break that seal,
how are we gonna re-pressurize?
MACE:
Cassie.
CASSIE:
Go.
MACE: Listen. We can't depressurize
when we open the airlock.
So the force of the gas
is gonna fire him out, right?
Right.
If you open your airlock and
we line it up right, he'll fire inside.
And so will we.
Without suits?
MACE: Get as close as you can.
-You'll have 20 meters to cover.
At minus 273 degrees Celsius.
MACE:
It's gonna be cold.
But we'll make it.
Anyone got any better ideas?
Copy that.
SEARLE:
Mace.
One problem.
The computer's down.
One of us has to manually
operate the seal.
MACE:
From inside.
Shit.
You're right.
So, whatever happens,
one of us is staying behind.
I see. I get it.
It's me.
That's what you're all thinking?
No, Harvey.
It's me.
You okay?
Hey, Capa.
We're only stardust.
CASSIE:
Mace, we're lined up.
Everything's set.
MACE:
Searle, are you ready?
All right.
We only got one shot at this.
Cassie.
-Are you ready?
CASSIE: Ready.
MACE: Harvey, keep your eyes shut
and exhale slowly.
HARVEY:
Copy.
MACE:
Let's do it.
[MACE PANTING]
[HARVEY GRUNTS]
[MACE GRUNTS]
[GRUNTS]
ICARUS:
Crew detected in airlock.
Recommend sealing
outer airlock door.
CAPA:
I lost Harvey. I lost Harvey.
-Harvey's gone.
ICARUS: Crew detected in airlock.
Sealing outer airlock door.
[MACE GRUNTS]
CORAZON:
Breathe, Mace. Just breathe.
MACE:
Get my hand. Get my hand.
-Breathe, Mace.
CASSIE: Capa?
CASSIE: You're okay, Mace.
You're okay, Mace. Please, breathe.
[MACE GROANING]
-Capa, are you all right?
-Yeah. Yeah.
CASSIE:
Let's get you out of here.
[SIGHING]
CASSIE [OVER COMM]:
Searle?
We're leaving now.
We're gonna complete the mission.
We're all thinking of you, Searle.
Searle?
We're gonna go now.
We love you.
[SEARLE GASPING]
[SEARLE SCREAMING]
MACE: I've been through Icarus's
activity file and I checked it.
Double-checked it.
Cory triple-checked it.
And it's the same results.
In other words, unless Icarus is deleting
her own files, she didn't do it.
And there was no malfunction
on the airlock hardware.
Which means the airlock
was decoupled manually.
Cassie and I were on the Flight Deck.
And I was with Capa and Searle.
And I think we can all assume
it wasn't Harvey.
Which leaves one possibility.
Trey.
Trey is so doped up
he can hardly walk or feed himself.
He sleeps for 23 hours a day.
And he blames himself for everything.
-Why would he do it?
MACE: We don't know.
The possibility remains that it was
him and we gotta take that seriously.
By doping him up more?
This isn't just about the possibility
whether he sabotaged the airlock.
There is something else too.
When Searle and Harvey died,
we lost two breathers.
If Trey dies...
...we'll have the oxygen
to make it to the delivery point.
At least now we know what happened
on Icarus I.
-The same thing that's happening here.
MACE: Fuck you, Capa.
What are you trying to remind us of?
Our lost humanity?
I'll do it.
I'm not passing any bucks.
Do it how?
That's between me and Trey.
We'll have a vote this time.
Unanimous decision required.
So you know where I stand.
And me.
What are you asking?
That we weigh the life of one
against the future of mankind?
Kill him.
CORAZON:
Cassie?
No.
-Cassie.
-I know the argument.
I know the logic.
You're saying you need my vote.
I'm saying you can't have it.
CORAZON:
What do we do?
Oh, God.
I'm sorry, Cassie.
You make it easy for him.
Somehow.
Find a kindness.
[SCALPEL WHIRRING]
Trey.
MACE [OVER PA]:
Everybody get here now.
[CAPA AND CORAZON GASP]
CASSIE:
He cut his wrists.
He took responsibility.
All these deaths.
Kaneda.
Searle. Harvey.
Trey.
None of them would have happened
if you hadn't diverted the mission.
-What do you want me to say?
-I don't want you to say shit.
I just want you to know that this...
...belongs here.
MACE:
Fuck you.
[BOTH GRUNTING]
[BOTH PANTING]
Air is low.
We need to limit our exertions.
CAPA: Icarus?
ICARUS: Yes, Capa?
CAPA: Run an update on biometric signs
for all crew.
Check oxygen consumption.
ICARUS:
Checking.
Thank you.
ICARUS:
Capa.
CAPA: Yes?
ICARUS: You are dying.
All crew are dying.
We know we're dying.
As long as we can live long enough
to deliver the payload...
...we're okay with it.
ICARUS:
Capa, warning.
You will not live long enough
to deliver the payload.
CAPA:
Please clarify.
ICARUS: Twelve hours before crew will
be unable to perform complex tasks.
Fourteen hours before crew will
be unable to perform basic tasks.
Sixteen hours until death.
Journey time to delivery point:
-Nineteen hours.
CAPA: Impossible. Corazon was certain.
We have remaining oxygen
to keep four crew alive.
Affirmative. Four crew could
survive on current reserves--
Trey is dead.
There are only four crew members.
ICARUS:
Negative.
Affirmative, Icarus. Four crew:
Mace, Cassie, Corazon and me.
ICARUS:
Five crew members.
Icarus?
ICARUS:
Yes?
Who's the fifth crew member?
ICARUS:
Unknown.
CAPA:
Where is the fifth crew member?
ICARUS:
In the Observation Room.
[CAPA PANTING]
[MAN GROANS]
MAN:
Are you an angel?
Has the time come?
I've been waiting so long.
CAPA:
Who are you?
MAN:
Who am I?
[MAN SIGHS]
MAN:
At the end of time...
...a moment will come
when just one man remains.
Then the moment will pass.
The man will be gone.
There will be nothing to show
that we were ever here...
...but stardust.
The last man, alone with God.
Am I that man?
CAPA:
My God.
My God, Pinbacker?
PINBACKER:
Not your God.
Mine.
[CAPA SCREAMS]
[CAPA GASPING]
CAPA:
Icarus. Full sunlight.
[PINBACKER SCREAMS]
Anyone.
[PINBACKER GRUNTING]
CAPA:
Oh, my God.
Icarus?
ICARUS: Warning, you do not have
authority to remove...
...the mainframe panels
from the coolant.
[VOICE DISTORTING]
Please return the panels to the coolant.
I cannot locate
your biometric signs.
Please identify yourself.
You gotta be kidding.
My God.
A baby.
A beautiful baby.
Icarus, patch me through to Mace.
I have something...
...wonderful to show him.
Or Cassie or Capa.
Icarus?
[SCALPEL WHIRRING]
[CORAZON GASPS]
PINBACKER:
Don't fight.
[CAPA GASPING]
[SCREAMS]
Mace?
CASSIE:
Capa?
MACE: Is anyone else getting silence
from Icarus?
Anybody?
CASSIE:
Capa?
[CASSIE GASPS]
[PINBACKER BREATHING]
Icarus, why are we in orbit?
Respond.
What?
Jesus Christ.
Capa? Capa?
MACE [OVER COMM]:
In the suit.
Use the hard link.
In the helmet.
CAPA:
Mace?
MACE: What the hell is going on?
CAPA: Mace?
I can't talk to Icarus.
CAPA: Pinbacker is onboard.
He's trying to stop the mission.
He's trying to destroy the mission.
He's insane.
[CASSIE WHIMPERING]
CAPA: Mace, listen.
I'm locked in the airlock.
MACE: Jesus Christ.
The mainframe is out of the coolant.
The mechanism is disabled.
I can't lower the mainframe panels.
Mace, repeat, please.
MACE:
Icarus is gonna burn out.
CAPA:
Mace.
Mace, come in.
[MACE GASPING]
[CASSIE SCREAMS]
[CASSIE SHOUTS]
[PINBACKER SCREAMING]
[ALARM BEEPING]
[MACE GASPING]
Come on.
MACE [OVER COMM]:
Capa.
-Capa.
-Mace?
We're in orbit. The computer is down.
I don't know if I can get her
back online.
You have to break us out
of orbit manually.
The only way to do that...
...is separate the payload.
Do you get it, Capa?
Force the bomb into the sun.
CAPA:
Separate the payload.
You'll have to get to the bomb
and detonate manually.
Unlock the airlock, do you copy?
Unlock the airlock.
I don't know how, just do it.
Just do it.
Okay.
I'm gonna do this.
Copy, Mace.
Copy.
[MACE GROANS]
[GRUNTING]
MACE:
Capa.
My leg.
[MACE GRUNTING]
Oh, God.
Do it, Capa.
Do it.
Mace.
[CAPA SHOUTS]
[SHOUTING]
[GASPING]
[SHOUTS]
[SCREAMS]
[GRUNTING]
Come on.
CASSIE:
Only dream I ever have.
Is it the surface of the sun?
Every time I shut my eyes
it's always the same.
[CAPA SCREAMS]
[GRUNTS]
[CAPA GRUNTING]
CAPA:
Cassie?
We're flying into the sun.
Cassie, there's not much time.
I need to know.
Where is he? Is he here?
[PINBACKER GRUNTING]
[CAPA SCREAMS]
PINBACKER:
For seven years I spoke with God.
He told me to take us all to heaven.
CASSIE:
No.
[PINBACKER SCREAMING]
[CAPA AND CASSIE SCREAMING]
[CAPA GRUNTING]
Finish it.
CAPA:
Let's say 25. Set at 25.
Please.
[GASPS]
[CAPA SHOUTING]
Hi, sis. Um....
Kiss the kids.
You guys, come on.
It's time.
CAPA:
So if you wake up one morning...
...and it's a particularly beautiful day,
you'll know we made it.
Okay.
I'm signing out.
[DISTRESS SIGNAL BEEPING]